Justin Heath Full-Stack Developer www.justcoder.co.uk

just.coder@outlook.com
Derby United Kingdom
www.linkedin.com/in/justcoder

Professional Statement

Passionate about implementing user-friendly applications with simple functionality but with a big impact on productivity and accuracy all supported by **23 years of experience**.

Over the past six years I have grafted my way from a novice frontend developer to a competent individual now leading a solo project at Bowler Eggs to deliver a **MEAN Stack** enterprise application to replace five legacy systems and databases. In my previous life as an accountant, I worked my way up to a 'Senior Costing Accountant'. In this role I was awarded the 'NHS HFMA costing award' two years running for my pioneering contribution to costing in the NHS that secured clinical engagement from consultants throughout the hospital. This led to national adoption, seeing many trusts in the UK looking to replicate the practices I blueprinted in HFMA reports and guidance.

I am very proud I decided to change my career to follow a belief that a role as a developer was the right path for me to take. I have shown a consistently positive attitude and drive to overcome the challenges of the role whilst crafting my skills. I have delivered some amazing applications that are making a real difference to the end users and improving processes/data for the organisations. My proudest achievement in the past six years is **teaching five frontend bootcamps with PurpleBeard** where I curated the teaching and learning material. In this time I mentored ten of the students directly which was great to combine my knowledge of coding, the engagement I receive while explaining technical problems and all my years in industry to see all ten secure employment as frontend developers.

I am seeking the perfect opportunity that will assist me in achieving my goal of becoming a senior software developer where I can support and guide the next generation of developers. In return you gain a passionate individual who is keen to grow with the department, years of soft skills harnessed ready to work closely with users to exceed their expectations. I complement these skills with a constant desire to learn and evolve where I never back down from a challenge and enjoy the opportunity to learn and share.

Skills

Programming languages:

APEX, HTML, CSS, SASS, JavaScript(OOP & ES6), TypeScript, Angular(SPA), React, React Native, Ionic, Redux (RxJs & NgRx), Bootstrap, Material UI, PrimNG, Node.js, npm, Python, Django express.js.

Debugging:

Proficient user of devtools for identifying bugs and understand the Stack & HEAP. React, Angular and Redux chrome devtool plugins.

Data Management:

SQL (SQL Server, T-SQL and PostgreSQL), Redgate SQL search. Visual Studio Suite (SSAS, SSRS, SSIS). MongoDB (NoSQL), Mongoose, ATLAS, Data Lakes & Triggers.

Problem solving:

Skilled in bridging the gap between creative concepts from UX designers and practical front-end implementation.

Lifecycle:

Hosting Heroku & Netlify, DevOps, CI/CD Pipeline, unit testing using Karma/Jasmine, Rest API testing using Postman, agile process JIRA. Version control GIT & GITHub.

Leadership:

Trained and mentored interns/placement students. I taught 5 cohorts frontend courses & mentored 10 students into employment.

Working examples of these skills on my portfolio site www.justcoder.co.uk

Recent Projects

End to End Industry System (Solo Project)

- Converting several SQL databases over to MongoDB and building 1 MEAN Stack application that
 will replace 5 legacy systems to be used by staff and access externally by clients. I was the sole
 lead developer on this project creating and building all the application while at the same time
 covering their in-house database manager and assisting him with the design of the data structure.
- The benefit this realised: Centralised 15 years of industry development into one system that allows one truth to be visualised by clients, shareholders and staff alike. All the data and documents from the past 15 years have been preserved and transferred over to MongoDB hosted on ATLAS which will see huge cost savings for the business.

Design & Delivered FrontEnd Bootcamp Material (Collaboration Project)

- Worked closely with the team at PurpleBeard to design class and teaching material. Introduced new concepts like quizzes and talking through class projects that helped with engagement, understanding of concepts and led to the students delivering much more complex projects.
- The benefit this realised: With the success of the courses being delivered Purplebard has been able to secure many more government contracts and help many students into employment.

Nottinghamshire COVID Vaccination Programme (Joint Project)

- Scoped, designed and built a vaccination CRUD page within the site to run off lists of patients to
 contact to invite for C19 vaccine. The complexity in this project was the restrictions of the cohort
 of patients to invite i.e. certain underlying illnesses, age groups, etc.
- The benefit this realised: Prevention of hundreds if not thousands of staff members having to individually go into each patient record to ensure they qualified for an invite. My web app automated the process, improved accuracy and prevented wrongly sent invites therefore patients where not refused the vaccine at vaccine centres (which was the most common process in other counties i.e. invite then reject once reviewed at the centre).

Education

NorthCoders

Software Developer (2021 - 2023)BSC level 4 Apprenticeship Certificate

Purple Beard Training

Coding Boot Camp (2021 Jan - Mar) w3school Front-End Certificate

Kaplan Online

Accounting AAT (2010 - 2014) Level 2,3 & 4

Derby University

A Levels (2001 - 2003)
Maths, Physics & Computer Science

The Ecclesbourne School GCSE (1990-96) GNVQ (1996-98)

Interests

Motor Racing, Rugby, Tennis & Golf. Walking and Running with my dog. National model car racing champion. Networking with the Tech Community.

Relevant Experience

Lead Developer – Bowler Eggs - 2021 –

Company Description – Supply chicken flocks and feed for the production of eggs sold onto the retailer.

Project – Implement the design and build of system for staff and clients to track the lifecycle of egg production.

Technologies – APEX, HTML, CSS, JavaScript, TypeScript, Angular, RxJs, NgRx, Material, Bootstrap, PrimeNG, Node.js, Express.js, Mongoose, MongoDB, Atlas, SQL, Heroku, GIT, GITHub, Agile practices recorded in JIRA, SOLID & DRY Principles.

Description

- Successfully managed a major IT project to replace the company's legacy systems, leading user design and building of an application dashboard.
- Consolidated fifteen years of data into a MongoDB database by leveraging my SQL expertise.
- Delivered the system on time within 24 months, allowing Bowlers Eggs to effectively track egg production with one sole system used by staff and clients.

Teacher - PurpleBeard - 2021 - 2022

Company Description – Startup organisation delivering government funded modern technology training.

Project – Deliver a frontend bootcamp to 50 students and create the material for this process.

Technologies - HTML, CSS, JavaScript(implementing OOP, FETCH & Asynchronous Behaviours), Bootstrap, Material, React.is.

Description

- Led the overhaul of PurpleBeard's bootcamp program, drastically increasing student retention rates from 40% to 80% and more students successfully passing the course.
- Developed a comprehensive syllabus and training approach that dramatically improved comprehension among students who completed the bootcamp.
- Engineered meaningful learning experiences to boost engagement and ensure students developed technical projects at the end of the training.

Principal Web App Developer - Nottingham & Nottinghamshire CCG - 2017 - 2021

Company Description – Control the funding for all healthcare in Nottinghamshire.

Project – A centralised healthcare system owned by the GPs to improve patient experience and track comorbidities.

Technologies – DotNetNuke, OpenWebStudio, HTML, CSS, JavaScript, Bootstrap, React.js, Python, Django, SQL-Server, T-SQL, SSAS, SSRS, SSIS.

Description

- Utilized complex SQL queries to aggregate and carry out complex data operations on billion row datasets from the healthcare data warehouse.
- Led a successful transition from outdated DotNetNuke/OpenWebStudio system to a more efficient React frontend, improving application speed and functionality.
- Gained valuable insight into Health Service operations and identified potential areas for improvement by working closely with GPs, practice staff and data engineers.

Senior Accountant - Leeds Teaching Hospitals NHS Trust - 2015 - 2017

Company Description – *Primary acute healthcare provider in Leeds.*

Project – Seconded to take my achievements of clinical engagement at Nottingham Hospital and replicate this in Leeds.

Technologies - Excel, VBA, C#, QlikView, SQL-Server, T-SQL.

Description

- Led successful clinical engagement initiatives across the UK's 4th largest trust, Leeds Teaching Hospitals NHS Trust, which included 8
 clinical directors and produced measurable savings that improved patient care.
- Awarded HFMA Costing Award for second year running in recognition of the accomplishments at Nottingham and Leeds Teaching Hospitals NHS Trust.
- Collaborated with HFMA to provide guidance and articles on effective best practice strategies throughout different trusts in the UK.

Senior Accountant - Nottingham University Hospitals NHS Trust - 2007 - 2014

Company Description – Primary acute healthcare provider in Nottingham.

Project – Started as a junior accountant and worked my way up to a senior accountant.

Technologies - Excel, VBA, C#, Qlikview, SQL-Server, T-SQL.

Description

- Successfully established an automated process for accounting tasks, reducing manual labour by manually creating tens of thousands rows for input and streamlining the department.
- Spearheaded a paperless transformation within the finance department, improving efficiency and saving the trust valuable resources and improving accuracy of data.
- Demonstrated natural leadership skills while working in various departments, leading to multiple promotions until I took on the role
 of Senior Costings Accountant.
- Fostered collaboration with different departments, building strong relationships and gaining recognition from the Director of Finance.